Miles Abbason

**** 919-830-7487

miles.abbason@gmail.com

mabbason

www.mabbason.com

Summary

I'm a full stack software engineer with experience developing serverless, globally distributed cloud applications. I recently built Seymour, an active monitoring solution on Amazon Web Services. Prior to this I founded and grew several small businesses in the foodservice space, one of which was a franchise across 14 states.

Experience

2022 – present **Seymour** *Co-Creator, Software Engineer*

- Co-created, Seymour, an open-source, easy-to-configure active monitoring solution that specializes in synthetic API testing and is deployed to Amazon Web Services
- Implemented a globally distributed approach to schedule API tests using AWS Lambda, Amazon EventBridge, AWS SNS, AWS SQS, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, and Amazon RDS
- Developed a multi-region parallel approach to running tests to hit API endpoints and compare the response to configured assertions by utilizing serverless architecture
- Reduced serverless system load by leveraging custom message attributes with Amazon Simple Notification Service (SNS) topic subscription filtering
- Authored full system multi-region automated deployment of Seymour Amazon resources by utilizing AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK) to implement Amazon CloudFormation
- Bypassed CDK deployment limitations by employing AWS SDK at runtime to connect resources across different regions
- Co-authored Seymour case study: https://seymour-active-monitoring.github.io/

2018 – present **Self-employed, Crucis Capital** Full Stack Web Developer

- Implemented open-source software with technologies such as Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Docker, JavaScript (ES6), React, MongoDB, HTML, and CSS
- Developed long/short hybrid swing trading program in C# for the NinjaTrader ecosystem
- Authored 20+ financial market indicators and short-term automated trading strategies
- Trelloha A Trello-inspired Kanban board for project management built with React, Redux, Express, MongoDB, and Node.js. Enables creating, editing, and deleting boards, lists, and cards
- Snaggl a RequestBin-like tool for webhooks built with MERN stack on Digital Ocean with Nginx, PM2, and ngrok

2011 – 2018 Self-employed, Pelican's SnoBalls

Co-Chief Executive Officer

- Spearheaded aggressive company growth from 85 franchisees to 176 over a two-year span
- Orchestrated geographic expansion into 7 new states
- Developed both franchise and business legal strategy from inception for franchise system in 14 states
- Established financial infrastructure, processes, and controls from inception for 2 separate legal entities
- Launched a nationwide digital and print rebranding campaign for 164 locations
- Initiated franchise core-process documentation by developing a comprehensive owner's manual
- Founder and Operator: Early-stage franchisee for 2 locations in Durham, NC

Education

2007 – 2009 California State University East Bay

BA Cum Laude, Graphic Design; GPA 3.77

Skills

Languages and frameworks

JavaScript (ES6), Node.js, Go, Express, React, Redux, PostgreSQL, C#, MongoDB

Cloud

AWS Lambda, AWS SQS, AWS SNS, Amazon EventBridge, AWS Elastic Beanstalk AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK), Digital Ocean AWS Relational Database Service

Other Technologies

HTTP, REST, APIS, Git/GitHub, MVC, Event-Driven Architecture, Docker, Adobe Suite, Linux HTML, CSS